Pioneer. Genius. Rebel.
Radioactive is a drama, romance, history film directed by Marjane Satrapi.
The story of Nobel Prize winner Marie Curie and her extraordinary scientific discoveries—through the prism of her marriage to
husband Pierre—and the seismic and transformative effects their discovery of radium had on the 20th century.
Marie Curie, played by Rosamund Pike.
Pierre Curie, played by Sam Riley.
Paul Langevin, played by Aneurin Barnard.
Professor Lippmann, played by Simon Russell Beale.
Jeanne Langevin, played by Katherine Parkinson.
Bronia Sklodowska, played by Sian Brooke.
Radioactive is a 2019 British biographical drama film
starring Rosamund Pike as Marie Curie.
It was directed by Marjane Satrapi and written by Jack Thorne, who adapted the 2010 graphic novel
Radioactive: Marie & Pierre Curie: A Tale of Love and Fallout by the American artist Lauren Redniss.
The film premiered as the Closing Night Gala at the
2019 Toronto International Film Festival.
The film was scheduled to be released in cinemas in 2020, but its
opening was cancelled due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
It was released digitally in the United Kingdom on 15 June 2020 by StudioCanal and began
streaming on Amazon Prime Video in the United States on 24 July 2020.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, nobel prize,
biography, based on true story, woman scientist.
The tone is emotional.